So I'm going to tell you a little bit
سوف احدثكم قليلا
about reimagining food.
عن اعادة تصور الغذاء
I've been interested in food for a long time.
انا مهتم بالطعام منذ زمن طويل
I taught myself to cook
علمت نفسي الطبخ
with a bunch of big books like this.
بواسطة بعض الكتب الكبيره كهذه
I went to chef school in France.
ذهبت الى مدرسة الطهاه في فرنسا
And there is a way
ويوجد هناك اسلوب
the world both envisions food,
يتصور به العالم الغذاء,
the way the world writes about food and learns about food.
الاسلوب الذي يكتب به العالم عن الغذاء ويتعلم عن الغذاء
And it's largely what you would find in these books.
وهو ماسوف تجده بشكل واسع في تلك الكتب.
And it's a wonderful thing.
وذلك شيئ رائع.
But there's some things that have been going on
لكن هناك شيئ ما يجري
since this idea of food was established.
منذ ان تأسست فكرة الغذاء
In the last 20 years,
في العشرين سنة الماضية
people have realized that science
ادرك الناس ان العلم
has a tremendous amount to do with food.
لديه الكثير ليقدمه في مجال الغذاء
In fact, understanding why cooking works
في الحقيقة, لتتمكن من فهم لماذا ينجح الطبخ,
requires knowing the science of cooking --
يتطلب معرفة بعلم الطبخ--
some of the chemistry, some of the physics and so forth.
بعض علم الكيمياء’بعض علم الفيزياء, وهكذا.
But that's not in any of those books.
لكن ذلك غير موجود في اي من تلك الكتب.
There's also a tremendous number of techniques
وهناك ايضا عدد هائل من التقنيات
that chefs have developed,
التي طورها الطهاه,
some about new aesthetics, new approaches to food.
يتعلق بعضها بجماليات, ونهج الغذاء.
There's a chef in Spain named Ferran Adria.
هناك طاهي في اسبانيا اسمه فيران ادريا
He's developed a very avant-garde cuisine.
طور مطبخ طليعي جدا
A guy in England called Heston Blumenthal,
ورجل في انجلترا يسمى هيلسون بلومينثال,
he's developed his avant-garde cuisine.
طور مطبخه الطليعي الخاص به.
None of the techniques that these people have developed
لا توجد اي من التقنيات التي طورها اولئك الاشخاص
over the course of the last 20 years
طوال العشرين سنه الماضية
is in any of those books.
في اي من تلك الكتب
None of them are taught in cooking schools.
لا يهتم اي منها بمدارس الطبخ.
In order to learn them, you have to go work in those restaurants.
لكي تتعلمها, يجب عليك الذهاب والعمل في تلك المطاعم
And finally,
واخيرأ
there's the old way of viewing food
تلك هي الطريقة القديمة لعرض الغذاء
is the old way.
انها طريقة قديمة.
And so a few years ago -- fours years ago, actually --
ومنذ عدة سنوات مضت-- اربع سنوات على وجه التحديد--
I set out to say, is there a way
كنت اقول ,هل يوجد هناك طريقة
we can communicate science and technique and wonder?
يمكننا بها ربط العلم والتقنية و الادهاش
Is there a way we can show people food
هل يوجد هناك طريقة نعرض بها الغذاء للناس
in a way they have not seen it before?
بطريقة لم يشاهدوها من قبل؟
So we tried, and I'll show you what we came up with.
لذلك حاولنا ,وسوف اعرض عليكم مالذي توصلنا اليه.
This is a picture called a cutaway.
هذه صورة سميناها المقطع.
This is actually the first picture I took in the book.
هذه في الواقع اول صوره التقطها في الكتاب.
The idea here is to explain what happens
الفكره هنا ان نشرح ماذا يحصل
when you steam broccoli.
عندما نطبخ البركلي على البخار.
And this magic view allows you to see
وهذ المنظر السحري يمكنكم من رؤية
all of what's happening
جميع ما يحصل
while the broccoli steams.
بينما يطبخ البروكلي على البخار.
Then each of the different little pieces around it
وكل من الاجزاء الصغيره حولها
explain some fact.
تشرح حقيقه ما.
And the hope was two-fold.
والامنيه كانت من شقين
One is you can actually explain what happens when you steam broccoli.
الشق الاول ,ان تتمكن من شرح مالذي يحدث عندما تطبخ البروكلي على البخار
But the other thing is that maybe we could seduce people
والشق الاخر هو احتمالية جذب الناس
into stuff that was a little more technical,
الى اشياء تقنية الى حد ما,
maybe a little bit more scientific, maybe a little bit more chef-y
واحيانا اشياء علمية, واشياء خاصة بفن الطبخ
than they otherwise would have.
اكثر مما تعودو عليه.
Because with that beautiful photo,
لانه بتلك الصورة الجميله,
maybe I can also package this little box here
ربما بامكاني اضافة هذا الصندوق الصغير
that talks about how steaming and boiling
الذي يعبر كيف ان التبخير والغليان
actually take different amounts of time.
في الواقع يستغرقان مقادير مختلفة من الوقت
Steaming ought to be faster.
الطهي على البخار يجب ان يكون اسرع
It turns out it isn't because of something called film condensation,
يبدو ان ذلك ليس بسبب شيء يسمى غشاء التكثيف,
and this explains that.
وهذا يعطي تفسيرا لذلك
Well, that first cutaway picture worked,
حسنا, تلك اول صورة مقطع يتم انجازها
so we said, "Okay, let's do some more."
وقلنا "حسنا , دعونا نقوم بالمزيد"
So here's another one.
هذه صوره اخرى
We discovered why woks are the shape they are.
اكتشفنا لماذا المقليات لها ذلك الشكل
This shaped wok doesn't work very well;
ذلك الشكل للمقالي لا يفي بالغرض بذلك القدر
this caught fire three times.
انه ياخذ ثلاثة اضعاف كمية النار.
But we had a philosophy,
لكن لدينا فلسفه
which is it only has to look good for a thousandth of a second.
تقول انه يجب ان يكون المنظر جميلا للجزء الالف من الثانيه
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And one of our canning cutaways.
احد مقاطعنا المعلبه
Once you start cutting things in half, you kind of get carried away,
حالما تبدا في قطع الاشياء الى نصفين , يصبح ذلك نوع من الهوس,
so you see we cut the jars in half as well as the pan.
كما تشاهدون قطعنا البرطمان بالنصف كما هو الحال بالنسبة للحوض
And each of these text blocks
وكل من تلك المربعات النصيه
explains a key thing that's going on.
تشرح حقيقة لما يحصل
In this case, boiling water canning
في هذه الحالة غلي الاغذية المعلبه
is for canning things that are already pretty acidic.
نقوم بذلك للاشياء الحامضية نوعا ما.
You don't have to heat them up as hot
لا يتوجب عليك تسخينها بشكل عالي
as you would something you do pressure canning
حيث انك تضغط المعلبات
because bacterial spores can't grow in the acid.
لان الجراثيم البكتيريه لا تنمو في الحامض.
So this is great for pickled vegetables,
هذه خضروات مختاره بعنايه
which is what we're canning here.
وهي ما نقوم بتعليبها هنا.
Here's our hamburger cutaway.
هذا هو مقطع الهمبرجر
One of our philosophies in the book
احد فلسفاتنا في هذا الكتاب
is that no dish
هو انه لا يوجد طبق
is really intrinsically any better than any other dish.
يمكن اعتبارها بشكل جوهري افضل من طبق اخر
So you can lavish
لذلك يمكنك الانعام عليهم
all the same care, all the same technique,
جميعا بنفس العناية ونفس التقنية,
on a hamburger
على الهمبرجر
as you would on some much more fancy dish.
بنفس القدر كم هو الحال على اي طبق فاخر اخر.
And if you do lavish as much technique as possible,
واذا حاولت المبالغة في التقنية بقدر الامكان
and you try to make the highest quality hamburger,
محاولا عمل الهمبرجر الاعلى جوده,
it gets to be a little bit involved.
يصبح ذلك اكثر مشاركة.
The New York Times ran a piece
صحيفة النيويورك تايمز كتبت عنوانا
after my book was delayed
بعد ان تأخر كتابي
and it was called "The Wait for the 30-Hour Hamburger
وكان يقول " انتظار الهمبرجر ذو الـ 30 ساعة
Just Got Longer."
تأخر اكثر."
Because our hamburger recipe, our ultimate hamburger recipe,
لان وصفة الهمبرجر الخاصة بنا ,وصفة الهمبرجر الافضل,
if you make the buns and you marinate the meat and you do all this stuff,
لانه اذا صنعت الكعكة ونقعت اللحم في الخل, اذا قمت بكل هذا
it does take about 30 hours.
سوف يستغرق ذلك 30 ساعة.
Of course, you're not actually working the whole time.
بالطبع ,لن تكون في عمل دائم طوال هذه المده.
Most of the time is kind of sitting there.
معظم الوقت انت فقط تجلس وتنتظر.
The point of this cutaway
المغزى من هذا الصورة المقطعية
is to show people a view of hamburgers they haven't seen before
هو ان تعرض للناس منظر للهمبرجر لم يشاهدوه من قبل
and to explain the physics of hamburgers
وان تشرح فيزياء الهمبرجر
and the chemistry of hamburgers,
وكيمياء الهمبرجر
because, believe it or not, there is something to the physics and chemistry --
لانه صدق او لا تصدق, يوجد علاقة للفيزياء والكيمياء,
in particular, those flames underneath the burger.
خذ مثلا, ذلك اللهب اسفل الهمبرجر,
Most of the characteristic char-grilled taste
معظم طعم الشواء الفحمي
doesn't come from the wood or the charcoal.
لا يأتي من الحطب او الفحم.
Buying mesquite charcoal will not actually make that much difference.
شراء اللحم النباتي لن يضفي اي اختلاف.
Mostly it comes from fat pyrolyzing, or burning.
معظم الطعم يأتي من التحلل الحراري اوالحرق.
So it's the fat that drips down and flares up
اذا هو الشحم الذي يتساقط ويشتعل
that causes the characteristic taste.
ذلك ما يعطي الطعم المميز
Now you might wonder, how do we make these cutaways?
لربما تتساءل الان كيف قمنا بتلك الصور المقطعية
Most people assume we use Photoshop.
معظم الناس يفترضون اننا نستخدم برنامج الفوتو شوب.
And the answer is: no, not really;
والجواب هو لا,
we use a machine shop.
نحن نستخدم معدات.
And it turns out, the best way to cut things in half
واكتشفنا انه افضل طريقة لقطع الاشياء الى نصفين
is to actually cut them in half.
هو في الواقع قطعها الى نصفين.
So we have two halves of one of the best kitchens in the world.
اذا لدينا نصفين لواحد من افضل المطابخ في العالم
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We cut a $5,000 restaurant oven in half.
قمنا بقطع ما قيمته 5000 دولار الى نصفين.
The manufacturer said,
الشركة المصنعه قالت,
"What would it take for you to cut one in half?"
"مالعائد عليكم من قطع الاشياء الى نصفين؟"
I said, "It would have to show up free."
اجبت, " سيكون ذلك بدون مقابل"
And so it showed up, we used it a little while,
تم عمل ذلك, واستخدمناه لوقت بسيط,
we cut it in half.
قطعناه الى نصفين.
Now you can also see a little bit how we did some of these shots.
يمكنكم الان مشاهدة كيف كمنا بالتقاط بعض تلك الصور.
We would glue a piece of Pyrex
قمنا بالصاق قطعه من البايريكس
or heat-resistant glass in front.
او الزجاج المقاوم للحرارة في الامام.
We used a red, very high-temperature silicon to do that.
استخدمنا سيلكون احمر يتحمل الحرارة العالية لعمل ذلك
The great thing is, when you cut something in half,
الشيء العظيم في ذلك انك عندما تقطع شيء الى نصفين
you have another half.
يكون لديك النصف الاخر.
So you photograph that in exactly the same position,
فتقوم بتصويره في نفس المكان
and then you can substitute in --
وتقوم بالاستبدال
and that part does use Photoshop -- just the edges.
وهذا الجزء الذي الذي استخدمنا فيه الفوتوشوب-- فقط الحواف.
So it's very much like in a Hollywood movie
ذلك يشابه الى حد كبير افلام هوليود
where a guy flies through the air, supported by wires,
حيث يكون الرجل طائرا في الهواء , مدعما باسلاك,
and then they take the wires away digitally
ومن ثم يتخلصون من الاسلاك باستخدام الكمبيوتر
so you're flying through the air.
فتصبح طائرا في الهواء
In most cases, though, there was no glass.
في معظم الحالات يوجد هناك زجاج
Like for the hamburger, we just cut the damn barbecue.
تماما مثل حالة الهمبرجر, قمنا فقط بقطع المشوى
And so those coals that kept falling off the edge,
وتلك الفحمات التي تساقطت من الحواف
we kept having to put them back up.
قمنا بارجاعها
But again, it only has to work for a thousandth of a second.
ولكن مره اخرى كان ذلك لجزء من الف من الثانيه
The wok shot caught fire three times.
حدث اشتعال في مكان العمل لثلاث مرات
What happens when you have your wok cut in half
الذي يحدث عندما يقطع عملك الى نصفين
is the oil goes down into the fire
ان الزيت يتسرب الى النار
and whoosh!
و تشتعل الحرائق
One of our cooks lost his eyebrows that way.
احد طباخينا فقد حاجبيه بهذه الطريقه
But hey, they grow back.
لكنها نمت مجددا
In addition to cutaways,
بالاضافة للمقاطع,
we also explain physics.
نقوم ايضا بشرح الفيزياء
This is Fourier's law of heat conduction.
قانون فوريور للتوصيل الحراري
It's a partial differential equation.
انها معادلة اشتقاقيه
We have the only cookbook in the world
نحن نمتلك كتاب الطبخ الوحيد في العالم
that has partial differential equations in it.
الذي يحتوي على معادله اشتقاقيه داخله
But to make them palatable,
لكن لجعلها مستساغه
we cut it out of a steel plate and put it in front of a fire
نقشناها على الحديد ووضعناها اما النار
and photographed it like this.
وصورناها كما تشاهدون.
We've got lots of little tidbits in the book.
لدينا الكثير من الحكايات الصغيره في الكتاب.
Everybody knows that your various appliances
كلنا يعلم ان الاجهزة المنزليه
have wattage, right?
لها قيمة واط صحيحة؟
But you probably don't know that much about James Watt.
لكنك لربما لا تعلم الكثير عن جيمس واط.
But now you will; we put a biography of James Watt in.
لكنك الان سوف تعلم, لقد وضعنا السيرة الذاتية الخاصه بـ جيمس واط في الكتاب
It's a little couple paragraphs
مقطعين صغيرين
to explain why we call that unit of heat the watt,
لنشرح لمذا نسمي وحدة الحراره بالواط
and where he got his inspiration.
وكيف حصل على الالهام
It turned out he was hired by a Scottish distillery
اتضح انه كان مستأجرا من مصنع تقطير اسكتلندي
to understand why they were burning so damn much peat
لفهم لماذا يحرقون الكثير من الخث النباتي
to distill the whiskey.
لتقطير الويسكي
We also did a lot of calculation.
قمنا ايضا بالعديد من الحسابات
I personally wrote thousands of lines of code
انا شخصيا كتبت الاف الاسطر
to write this cookbook.
لكتابة هذا الكتاب
Here's a calculation
هذه حسابات
that shows how the intensity of a barbecue,
تظهر كيف ان موقد الشواء
or other radiant heat source, goes
او اي من مصادر الاشعاع الحراري تتغير
as you move away from it.
كلما ابتعدت عنها
So as you move vertically away from this surface,
فكلما انتقلت عموديا من السطح
the heat falls off.
تنخفض الحرارة
As you move side to side, it moves off.
واذا تحركت من الجانب الى الجانب تنخفض ايضا
That horn-shaped region
تلك هي المنطقة المشابهه للبوق
is what we call the sweet spot.
ذلك ما نسميه المنطقة الحلوة
That's the place where the heat is even to within 10 percent.
هذا المكان حيث الحراراة في مدى 10 %
So that's the place where you really want to cook.
اذا هو المكان الذي تريد الطبخ فيه
And it's got this funny horn-shaped thing,
وكان له شكل البوق الجميل
which as far as I know, again,
وهو في حد علمي
the first cookbook to ever do this.
اول كتاب طبخ يقوم بهذا
Now it may also be the last cookbook that ever does it.
واظن انه سيكون اخر كتاب يقوم بذلك
You know, there's two ways
تعلمون ان هناك طريقتان
you can make a product.
يمكنك بهما عمل منتج
You can do lots of market research
يمكنك القيام بالكثير من البحث التسويقي
and do focus groups
وملاحظة المجموعات
and figure out what people really want,
وتتبين مالذي يريده الناس
or you can just kind of go for it
او ان تقوم بفعل ماتريده مباشره
and make the book you want and hope other people like it.
وان تقوم بعمل الكتاب كما تريد وتتأمل ان ينال اعجاب الناس
Here's a step-by-step that shows grinding hamburger.
هاهنا يظهر شواء الهمبرجر خطوة بخطوة
If you really want great hamburger,
اذا كنت بالفعل تريد الحصول على همبرجر رائع
it turns out it makes a difference if you align the grain.
اتضح ان هناك فرق يعتمد على تصفيف اللحم المفروم
And it's really simple, as you can see here.
وذلك بسيط جدا كما تشاهدون هنا
As it comes out of the grinder, you just have a little tray,
انه يخرج من المفرمه , ولديك صينية صغيرة
and you just take it off in little passes,
وتخرجه بتمريرات قصيرة
build it up, slice it vertically.
ترصها فوق بعضها البعض عموديا
Here's the final hamburger.
هاهو الهمبرجر النهائي
This is the 30-hour hamburger.
هذا هو همبرجر الـ 30 ساعه
We make every aspect of this burger.
قمنا بصنع كل محتويات هذا الهمبرجر
The lettuce has got liquid smoke infused into it.
الخس يحتوي على سائل مدخن في داخله
We also have things about how to make the bun.
ولدينا ايضا معلومات حول كيف تصنع الخبز
There's a mushroom, ketchup -- it goes on and on.
هناك فطر وكاتشاب وهكذا
Now watch closely. This is popcorn. I'll explain it here.
الان شاهدو حبة الفشار هذه, ساقوم بالشرح
The popcorn is illustrating
حبة الفشار تفسر
a key thing in physics.
مبدا فيزيائي اساسي
Isn't that beautiful?
اليس ذلك جميلا
We have a very high-speed camera,
لدينا كاميرا فائقة السرعة
which we had lots of fun with on the book.
مكنتنا من الحصول على الكثير من الاشياء الممتعه في الكتاب
The key physics principle here
المبدا الفيزيائي هنا
is when water boils to steam
هو انه عندم يغلي الماء ويتبخر
it expands by a factor of 1,600.
يتمدد بمعامل 1.600
That's what's happening to the water inside that popcorn.
وهذا ما يحصل للماء داخل حبة الفشار
So it's a great illustration of that.
بالتالي تلك وسيلة شرح لذلك المبدأ
Now I'm going to close with a video that is kind of unusual.
الان سوف اختم بمقطع فيديو فريد من نوعه
We have a chapter on gels.
لدينا فصل خاص عن الجلي
And because people watch Mythbusters and CSI,
ولان الناس يتابعون مسليلات مايثبستر و سي اس اي
I thought, well, let's put in a recipe
فكرت انه لماذا لا نضع وصفة
for a ballistics gelatin.
لعمل كور الجيلاتين
Well, if you have a high-speed camera,
اذا كان لديك كاميرا سريعة
and you have a block of ballistics gelatin lying around,
ولديك قالب من الجيلاتين موضوع في مكان ما
pretty soon somebody does this.
لا بد وان يقوم احدهم بعمل هذا
(Gasps)
(لهاث)
Now the amazing thing here
الان الشيء الرائع هنا
is that a ballistics gelatin is supposed to mimic
انا الجيلاتين يفترض به ان يحاكي
what happens to human flesh when you get shot -- that's why you shouldn't get shot.
ما يحصل للجسم البشري عندما يصاب بطلقه -- ولذلك لا يجب عليك ان تصاب بطلق
The other amazing thing is, when this ballistics gelatin comes down,
الشيء الاخر الرائع عندم يسقط قالب الجيلاتين
it falls back down as a nice block.
يسقط مرة اخرى كقالب جميل
Anyway, here's the book.
على اية حال, هاهو الكتاب
Here it is.
ها هو
2,438 pages.
2348 صفحة
And they're nice big pages too.
وصفحات كبيرة وجميله
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
A friend of mine complained
صديق لي كان يعلق
that this was too big and too pretty to go in the kitchen,
انه كبير وجميل لا يليق بالمطبخ
so there's a sixth volume
هاهو المجلد السادس
that has washable, waterproof paper.
مصنوع من اوراق مضادة للماء وقابلة للغسل
(Applause)
(تصفيق)